

# Elena Gutiérrez

**Email:** elenagutiv@gmail.com

**LinkedIn:** <u>elena-gutierrez-viedma</u>

## Objective

Contribute to the solution and communication of the next generation of research challenges in the fields of program analysis and verification, machine learning and natural language processing applications; using my mathematical background and research experience on the theory of formal languages for software verification.

## **Computer Skills**

- o C, Python, Octave, Bash, Prolog, HTML, CSS | General experience
- C++, Java | Basic experience
- o Git, LaTex, Keynote
- Mac OS, Linux

# Work Experience

IMDEA Software Institute (Instituto Madrileño de Estudios Avanzados)

Researcher (predoctoral researcher until Sep. 2020)

Madrid, Spain
Sep. 2016 - present

National Institute of Informatics

Erato MMSD (Metamathematics for System Design) Project

6-months research internship

Tokyo, Japan

May. 2019 - Nov. 2019

IMDEA Software InstituteMadrid, Spain3-month research internshipssummers 2013, 2014 and 2015

#### Education

Ph.D. in Software, Systems and Computing

With cum laude distinction

Double Degree in Mathematics and Software Engineering

Average grade: 8.2/10

Univ. Politécnica de Madrid

Sep. 2016 - Sep. 2020

Univ. Autónoma de Madrid

Sep. 2011 - May. 2016

#### **Courses and Certificates**

Course on Machine Learning by Andrew Ng - Coursera
 School on Formal Verification - The Hebrew University (Jerusalem)
 TOEFL iBT | Test score: 104/120
 Mar. 2020 - present
 17 - 21 Dec. 2017
 Feb. 2016

# **Software Projects**

- o Genetic algorithm (in C) for the analysis of recurrent neural networks (2020). GitHub
- o Optimization algorithm (in Prolog) for Horn clause programs (2016). GitHub

Ph.D. Thesis New Perspectives on Classical Automata Constructions Sep. 2020

Natural Languages Spanish | Native English | Advanced French | Basic

#### **Volunteer Work and Interests**

- Soñar Despierto Foundation: Giving support lessons to high-school students coming from marginalised backgrounds in Madrid (Sep. 2018 - May. 2019)
- AFS Intercultura Spain: Participating in the coordination of intercultural activities with foreign students from exchange programs (Sep. 2011 - May. 2012)
- I love sports, especially running (medium: 10 km, and large distance: 21 km), cycling and paddle tennis.